APARNA SANTHOSH NAIR

Bangalore | 3.aparna@gmail.com | 9538242229

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced writer and editor who understands what it takes for a piece of content to click with the audience. A grammar Nazi who is not shy of adapting her style to suit the intended purpose of the content. Adept at handling a team of people and bringing out the best in them professionally. Learner for life.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Develop, manage and curate content for website
- Incorporate SEO elements to generate traffic and leads
- Knowledge of Google Analytics, SEO tools, basic WordPress
- Email and SMS marketing through CRM tool
- Produce good, original written content for various content marketing collaterals
- Good command of English grammar and proficiency in writing long/short forms of content
- Lead and train a team of writers
- Excellent communication skills

EXPERIENCE

BYJU'S (Think N Learn Pvt Ltd.)

Senior Manager, Content | Dec 2016 - Present

As Senior Manager, Content, my job is to make sure that accurate, timely and relevant content goes up the BYJU'S UPSC (IAS) test prep website. I am responsible for allocating written tasks to the writers in my team. I edit and review their work, and also optimize the content for SEO relevancy. The content includes subject-specific content based on the UPSC syllabus, exam-related information and notifications, and also general articles including tips and how-to articles. I also write content including subject-specific and promotional content based on requirement. As part of the role, I also frame emailers and text messages for promotions, apart from working on the BYJU'S UPSC test prep YouTube channel.

Capital IQ (Division of S&P's)

Research Associate | Jun 2008 - Aug 2010

Secondary research online for company database

EDUCATION

MBA (HR, Marketing)

Delhi Institute of Advanced Studies, Delhi | 2006 - 2008

B.Sc. Chemistry

Ethiraj College for Women, Chennai | 2002 - 2005

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- UGC NET Qualified (Subject: Management) (2018)
- 'Certificate in IT' from NIIT, New Delhi (2006)
- 'Certificate in Clinical Trials' from Ethiraj College in association with Apollo Hospitals, Chennai (2005)
- 'Certificate in Spanish as a Foreign Language' from Institute Hispania, New Delhi (2005)

LANGUAGES

• English, Hindi, Malayalam, Basic Tamil, Basic Sanskrit, Basic Spanish

INTERESTS

Reading, writing, marketing, history, debating, music